# Jacob Beeson

Software Developer

### Contact

**Address** 

Austin, TX, 78724

**Phone** 

(336) 486-3317

E-mail

boxnbeeson@gmail.com

LinkedIn

https://tinyurl.com/JPBLIn

**Portfolio** 

https://tinyurl.com/JPBPort

#### **Skills**

React.js

Node.is

**Express** 

**JQuery** 

Inquirer

Handlebar.js

MySQL

MongoDB

Bootstrap

HTML

CSS

**JavaScript** 

Software developer utilizing a bachelor's degree in psychology to analyze client demographics for producing effective web design and user experience. Obtained a MERN Full-Stack Certificate through the University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill. Known for leadership qualities and taking initiative. Successfully led a large organization while in university, restructuring its design based off of attracted demographics while also increasing its membership and community outreach. Proven teamwork capabilities, adaptive nature, and strong interpersonal communication skills through multiple projects.

#### **Education**

Certificate In Full Stack Web Development
The Hong Kong University of Science And Technology MERN and Bootstrap 4
Certificate in Full Stack Web Development
University Of North Carolina At Chapel Hill
MERN (Mongo, Express, React, Node.js)
Bachelor of Arts: Psychology
University Of North Carolina At Chapel Hill

## **Projects**

#### **PROJECTS**

<u>CoffeeHut</u> | https://tinyurl.com/CoffeeHutGH **Livelink:** https://tinyurl.com/CoffeeHutApp

- Summary: Web-based application where users may customize and order drinks from a local coffee shop
- Role: Front-end development
- Tools: HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, MySQL, Handlebars, Fontawesome

<u>React.js Portfolio</u> | https://tinyurl.com/RPortGH

Livelink: https://tinyurl.com/ReactPGH

- Summary: Portfolio designed using React.js
- Role: Sole Developer
- Tools: React.js, HTML, CSS, JavaScript

**README Generator** | https://tinyurl.com/rmgGH

**Tutorial:** https://tinyurl.com/rmgtutorial

- Summary: CLI application that a client may use to easily create pre-formatted README.md files
- Role: Sole Developer
- Tools: JavaScript, inquirer, cli

**Dinner Dice** | https://tinyurl.com/DinDiceGH

**Livelink:** https://tinyurl.com/DinDiceApp

- Summary: Entertainment application allowing users to try new dinner and drink recipes for date night
- Role: Back-end development
- Tools: HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, jQuery, thecocktaildb/themealdb APIs

Weather Dashboard | https://tinyurl.com/WDashGH

**Livelink:** https://tinyurl.com/WDashApp

- Summary: Weather application allowing users to search cities current broadcast and 5-day forecast
- Role: Sole Developer
- Tools: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, AJAX, API integration

## **Professional Experience & Community Involvement**

2014-01 -President, Assistant Coach, Vice-President, Head Trainer, Team Captain, Secretary 2019-05

Carolina Boxing Club

- 2000+ hours of hands-on training with individuals and groups
- Instructed and supervised team of 10-15 trainers
- Provided daily updates and instructions to a club of 75 -150 people
- Constructed daily boxing technique, conditioning, and training plans

2016-06 -Security / Bartender 2019-05

Pantana Bob's

- Fostered teamwork and leadership skills for a high-stress environment
- Developed the ability to defuse violent situations and resolve issues among patrons